+234 (90) 58338298 | Daniellawal2001@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/Daniellawal/ Github.com/DaniellawalT

Excel

Profile Summary

Dedicated, teamwork-oriented, results-driven and responsible Data Analyst with significant experience in increasing comprehension of reports and presentations, highly educated, a Bachelor's in computer science, a Professional certification in data science and analysis. My journey as a data analyst has equipped me with the skills to clean and manipulate data, perform in-depth analysis, and communicate findings effectively to both technical and non-technical audiences. I have experience working on diverse project.

Skills

Python SQL

Libraries: Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Software: MySQL, MS SQL Tools: Pivot Table, Pivot Chart, Ploty Server. VLOOKUP, HLOOKUP, VBA, Power

Query, Data (sorting, filtering) Power Bi HTML | CSS **Machine Learning:**

Tools: DAX, API, Power Query Supervised and Unsupervised Machine learning techniques

Projects

COVID- 19 VIRUS DATASET EDA - Personal Project

November 2023

- Utilized **Python** to analyze 306429 records and 8 rows in the dataset and gain insights on what countries were affected
- Implemented Unique method to find affected countries in the covid-19 dataset and return the key requirements as a
- Aggregated and visualized the data by using pandas, matplotlib and seaborn to compile a professional report

BIKE SALES DATA ON GENDER - Personal Project

November 2023

- Utilized Excel to perform bike sales data on gender of occupations, educations, incomes, marital status and home owners
- Performed pivot table and pivot chart to successfully identify between males and females.

FEATURES - Undergraduate Project

DETECTION OF PHISHING ATTACKS IN ONLINE TRANSACTION WEBSITE USING PLUGINS WITH DATA MINING

September 2022

- Performed manual feature selection based on the email structure and automated selection techniques.
- Utilized Kali Linux for simulation using social engineering tool kit for the site cloning
- Implemented Netcraft as for the use of data mining plugins

Work Experience

DATALINKS FINANCE AND SYSTEMS CONSULTING LIMITED - Data Analyst

April 2024 - Present

Utilized Microsoft SQL Server 2016/2019 and SQL Azure development tools to develop tailored business intelligence (BI) solutions.

TECH STUDIO ACADEMY- Data analyst - Internship

July 2023 - March 2024

- Converted data into actionable insight by predicting and modeling future outcomes
- Utilized Python (Pandas, MatPlotLib, Numpy, and Ski-learn), SQL, Power Bi, and other dashboard/visualization toolsets for data intelligence and analysis.

DIGITAL AUTONOMY INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY LIMITED

May 2021 – October 2021

ICT NETWORK TECHNICIAN - Internship

- Supported to prevent customer service delays for basic technical issues as a basic end-user.
- Assisted in the maintenance of IT standards and documentation.
- Assisted with help desk calls.
- Performed computer imaging, staging and installation under IT staff guidance.

CLISTE EDGE CONSULTING Ltd - ICT - Part-Time

- Designed graphics flyer.
- Reviewed data and information collection.

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE – Mountain Top University

August 2023

Additional Training

- Data Science and Analysis Professional Course.
- SQL for Data Science.
- Certified Cisco Network Associate (CCNA).
- Java Programming, Android Application Development.
- Certified Ethical Hacker.
- Certificate in CompTIA A+
- Cloud Computing

Interests: Football | Adventurer | Photography | Volunteering